#Encodergasm Presents
～
Shut up!
うっ いててえっ
Ow...
あん？
（エド）ガオー！
（ベイカー）えっ？
ガォーッ
あ なっ…
W-What?
（エド）あむ
（ベイカー）うあああ！
Hey, Jet.
（スパイク）おい ジェット
（ジェット）うん？
着陸まで どのくらいだって
聞いてんだよ
I'm asking ya, how much longer before we land?
How long ya been standing there?
お前 いつから そこにいた？
さっきから いたぜ
I've been here for a while.
そうか
I see...
（フェイ）何 ぼさっとしてんのよ
私の賞金は まだなの？
What're ya spacing out about?
Where's my bounty?
Can't you land quickly so I can hand over that musty-looking fugitive?
さっさと上陸して
あの暑っ苦しい首 引き渡してよ
（スパイク）ん？ おい
まだ着陸許可も取ってねえのか？
What, you haven't even gotten permission to land yet?
I know.  You guys are so obnoxious.
分かってるよ　うるさい連中だな
Don't rush so much!
そう慌てなさんなよ
空港のほうは頼むぜ
And take care of the airport end for me.
I thought Ganymede was your homeland.
（フェイ）ガニメデって
あんたの ふるさとなんでしょ？
案外 昔 泣かせた女のことでも
思い出してたんじゃないの？
Were you perhaps thinking about some woman in the past that cried over you?
それとも
泣かされた女だったりして
...or perhaps a woman that made YOU cry.
うるせえって言ってんのが
聞こえねえのか！
Didn't ya hear me when I said you're being obnoxious?!
（ドネリー）はい
Yes...
This is Ganymede police.
こちらガニメデ警察
（ジェット）ドネリー
Donelly?
Oh, Jet!  Jet, it's you!
おお ジェット！ ジェットか
There is no mistake...
おいおい まちげえねえ
おつむは随分と
さっぱりしちまったが―
The top of your head's gotten rather lonely, but it's still Jet all right!
確かにジェットだ
久しぶりだな ドネリー
Long time no see, Donelly.
I'm surprised that you're working around here.  Has it been...
驚いたね
お前がここで働いていたなんぞ
かれこれ７～８年前か
Seven years?  Eight?
What the hell's up with you to come back so suddenly?
一体 どうしたってんだい？
こんな突然に
I wanna hand over a bounty.
賞金首を引き渡したいんだ
Wanted ad number EX41285.  Baker Panchorero.
手配番号 ＥＸ４１２８５
ベイカー･パンチョレロ
へえ お前さんが賞金稼ぎね
To think you're a bounty hunter...
You, who was called the Black Dog...
あの 食らいついたら
離さない狂犬―
“ブラックドッグ”と言われた
お前さんがか？
...a mad dog that never let go of things bitten into?
そっちこそ もうとっくに
リタイアしたと思ってたぜ
I thought YOU had already retired.
Hey, I'm still an active officer!
（ドネリー）何？ こちとら
まだまだ現役だぜ
Don't judge things on YOUR time scale, you Rip Van Winkle you.
てめえの早さで
時間 はかるもんじゃねえやい
このリップヴァンウィンクルめ
He used to be a cop?  That explains...
That example is completely reversed!
何？ 元警官だったわけ？
どうりで
（ジェット）例えが逆だ
何？ 元警官だったわけ？
どうりで
（ドネリー）そうか
まあいいや どっちでも
何？ 元警官だったわけ？
どうりで
（ドネリー）そうか
まあいいや どっちでも
何だ？
（ドネリー）そうか
まあいいや どっちでも
What?
I'm just glad to see yer still kickin'.
何だ？
（ドネリー）
元気そうで なによりだ
何だ？
（ドネリー）
元気そうで なによりだ
...why I don't get along with him.
Yeah, you, too.
（ドネリー）
元気そうで なによりだ
相性 悪いと思ったわ
（ジェット）
ああ あんたもね
そうだ 彼女は何て言ったっけ？
Oh yeah... what was her name...
You know...
ほら…
I know!  Alisa!
そう アリサ！
She's got a little joint in the port of Marvis.
（ドネリー）彼女 マルビスの港で
店やってんだよ
A small bar called "La Fin"...
“ラファン”っていう
小さな飲み屋だけどな
But in this recession, I hear she's got a lot of debts to pay...
でも この不景気だろ？
借金 抱えて苦労してるって話だが
まあ 女一人 生きていくにゃ
いろいろと あるだろうけどさ
I'm sure there are a lot of problems for a woman trying to live alone...
Sense of justice and duty, huh?
（フェイ）浪花節だねー 全く
First time in a while he's home, of course he's gonna go visit.
（スパイク）たまの故郷だ
会いにも行くさ
You're totally wrong if you think your old woman still thinks about you.
（フェイ）
昔の女が今でも自分のこと
考えてるなんて思ったら大間違いよ
女がみんな自分と同じだと思ったら
大間違いだぜ
～
You're totally wrong yourself if you think every other woman thinks like you.
浪花節節 かつお節ー
Justice and duty, duty, THREE O'CLOCK TEA!
Really, men...
（フェイ）本当 男って―
...are hopeless romantics.
どうしようもないロマンチストね
Hey, why are you rubbing that stuff on?
ねえねえ
なんで 塗り塗りしてるの？
Beautiful skin is maintained by continued effort that seems futile.
無駄とも思える努力の積み重ねが
美しい肌を維持する　分かる？
Do you understand?
ふーん
I know!  Futile!  Useless!
分かった！ 無駄だ 無駄ー
（フェイ）うーん
This is...
ここ ラファンだよな？
...La Fin, right?
Yeah... and you are?
（リント）ああ あんたは？
んんー 昔のなじみさ
An old friend.
久しぶりに こっちに来たんでね
I was in the area for the first time in a while...
Alisa... isn't here.
アリサは いない
（アリサ）ジェット
Jet?
That can't be...
まさか ジェットなの？
Are you really Jet?
Rhint...
リント この人は あたしの客よ
...he is my guest.
大丈夫
It's all right.
You don't mind?
いいのか？
I don't...
（アリサ）ええ
Anyway...
それより どう？
一杯 飲むでしょ？
How about it?  You want a glass, right?
You're my last customer.
あなたが最後の客よ
（ジェット）んん？
I'm closing shop.
（アリサ）店を閉めるの
The number of ships decreased, and this area has gotten desolate...
船が減って この辺りも
寂しくなっちゃったし―
I'm thinking of moving to a new town.
新しい町へ移ろうと思ってるの
Are you all right?
（ジェット）大丈夫なのか？
（アリサ）えっ？
On the new island cities, mortgage is expensive.
新しい水上都市じゃ
権利金なんかも高いし―
大変なんじゃないか？
Are you able to manage all that?
That's so like you to worry about such things.
あなたらしいわ
そんなこと気にして　フフッ
新しい町で気分を変えるつもり
I'm planning to change myself in the new town.
心配いらないわ　リントもいるし
Don't worry...
Rhint is here with me...
さっきの男か？
That guy that was just here?
Something on your mind?
気になる？
Yeah.
なるね
To tell the truth, I already have 3 kids...
実は もう子供が３人
フフフ 冗談よ 冗談
I'm just kidding.  It was a joke!
Rhint is just my boyfriend.
リントは ただの恋人
How are you doing?
あなた どうしてるの？
もう結婚した？
Have you gotten married yet?
I live and wander with a group of weirdos.
変なやつらと一緒に旅暮らしさ
And on top of it, I'm a bounty hunter now.
しがない賞金稼ぎってやつだ
Do you remember?
（ジェット）覚えてるか？
Where's Jet?
（ドネリー）ジェットは？
Doing personal stuff.
（スパイク）ちょいと やぼ用でね
You're his partner, right?
（ドネリー）あんた 相棒だよな？
Yeah.
（スパイク）ああ
I've got news on a bounty.
（ドネリー）賞金首の情報がある
This hasn't been publicly broadcast yet...
まだ表に流す前のものだ
んっ とっと とっとっと
Rhint Celonius.
（ドネリー）リント･セロニアス
マルビスの港のチンピラでな
A thug in the port of Marvis.
Last night, he contacted financial broker Law Rentzuo.
ゆうべ 金融ブローカーの
ローレンツォってやつを…
まあ こいつも
相当の悪なんだが―
This guy was another tough guy...
...but he was killed!
やっちまった
And so?
それで？
Rhint... is Alisa's gigolo.
リントはアリサの色なんだ
I thought I'd warn you guys.
知らせたほうがいいと思ってね
And how much is the bounty?
で 賞金額は？
ナァハ
Back then... when I got home from work...
（ジェット）
あの頃 俺が仕事から帰ると―
いつも お前が待っていた
You always waited for me.
That was all I needed.
俺にとっては それで十分だった
But that day...
でも あの日…
俺が帰ってきたら
その時計だけが残っていた
When I came home, only that watch was left...
たった ひと言―
...and a small note with one word: "farewell".
“さよなら”とだけ
書かれた手紙と一緒にな
For some reason, I didn't feel sad.
不思議と俺は
悲しみを感じなかった
ただ 現実感がないだけだった
It just lacked reality.
And I gradually felt something inside me go numb...
そして だんだんと自分の中で―
何かが まひしていくのを感じた
After 6 months, I made a bet with myself.
半年たって俺は賭けをした
That I would leave this planet if you didn't return...
もし この時計が止まったとき
まだお前が戻らなかったら―
この星を出ようって
...by the time this clock stopped.
お前を責めに来たんじゃない
I didn't come here to blame you.
I just wanted to know...
俺はただ 知りたかった
あのとき お前がいなくなった訳を
...why you disappeared back then.
あなたの中では―
You seem to think that time on Ganymede had stopped.
ガニメデの時間は
止まったままみたいね
That's a story from long ago.
遠い昔の話よ
もう忘れたわ
I've... forgotten it.
動かない時間は いらないわ
I don't need time that stands still.
さよなら ジェット
Farewell, Jet.
（荒い息）
（車のクラクション）
A bounty hunter?  Then can he be?
（リント）賞金稼ぎだって？
まさか…
Rhint...
（アリサ）リント
He's after me...
俺を探りに来たんだ
くそお 賞金を懸けられてるのか
I have a bounty on my head...
もう駄目だ
もう駄目だ！
It's all over!
It's not your fault.
（アリサ）あんたは悪くないわ
It's because I borrowed money from a guy like him...
あたしが あんなやつから
お金を借りたから
...and you protected me...
あたしを守ってくれたんじゃない
（リント）捕まったら
もう助からない
I can't be saved if I get caught.
I...
俺は―
...killed a guy...
殺しちまったんだぜ
逃げましょう
Let's get outta here...
（リント）えっ？
逃げるのよ ２人で！
Let's get outta here, just the two of us!
This must be because I have good karma...
俺って普段の行いが
いいからねえ
Sorry, but it's business.
悪いが商売なんでね
ハンドルを頼む！
Steer for me, please!
Hey?  What's wrong?!
（ジェット）おい どうした？
180万の首を追ってる
I'm after a bounty worth 1.8 million.
（ジェット）何？
What?!
Here, I'll send it to you.
（スパイク）今 そっちに送るぜ
He's a bounty?
やつが賞金首？
Yeah, a secret bit of info from Donelly.  He apparently killed a loan shark.
（スパイク）
ああ ドネリーからの裏情報だ
金貸しをやっちまったらしい
ああ くっそ！
Dammit!
（ジェット）俺がやる　お前は戻れ
I'll do this.  You can go back.
You're not gonna let him go, are you?
見逃すつもりじゃないだろうな
（ジェット）
ここは俺が警官だった土地だぜ
This is the land where I was a cop...
I'm the Black Dog...  Once I bite, I never let go.
食らいついたら離さない
ブラックドッグだ
女に未練はないが
この島のけりは俺がつける
I have no regrets about her, but I'll settle this score on my home turf.
Sense of justice and duty, huh...
浪花節だぜ 全く
（ジェット）聞こえるか？
Can you hear me...?
Stop the boat, now!
ボートをすぐ止めるんだ！
Jet?
（アリサ）ジェット？
（リント）くうう
～
Stay away!
（アリサ）来ないで！
Please, let us go!
お願い 逃して！
There are other bounties to find!
賞金首なんて他にもいるじゃない
Even if I let you go, someone will come for you someday...
俺が見逃しても―
いずれ誰かが来る
If you run, you will become an accomplice.
一緒に逃げれば
お前も共犯になっちまうんだ
（アリサ）来ないで！
一緒に逃げれば
お前も共犯になっちまうんだ
Stay away!
今なら まだ間に合う
You still have time.
Don't worry about me anymore!
もう構わないで！
（アリサの荒い息）
あの頃もそうだった
You were like this back then, too...
You decided everything.
何でも あなたが決めて
それが いつも正しくて
And you were always right...
When I was with you, I never had to do anything.
あなたといるとき
あたしは何もしなくてよかった
All I had to do was hang on to your arm like a child, with no cares in the world.
子供みたいに無邪気に―
あなたの腕に
つかまってればよかった
I wanted to decide how to live my life by myself...
あたしは
自分で生き方を決めたかったの
Even if that was a mistake...
たとえ それが間違ってたとしても
（リント）おわっ 離せよ！
ムショなんて嫌だ　離せ！
Let go!  I don't wanna go to prison!  Let go!!
Help!  Help me, please!
助けて　助けてくれよ 頼む
Be strong...
（ジェット）強くなれよ
...and protect her...
そして守ってやんな
Self-defense seems to be how they see it.
（ジェット）
正当防衛の線で堅いそうだ
What are you going to do now?
これから どうするんだ？
I won't be going anywhere anymore.
（アリサ）
もう どこへも行かないわ
I will wait in my store... for Rhint.
あの店でリントを待つつもり
It won't take long...
長くは かからないさ
...because time is flowing along.
時間は流れてるんだからな
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
An unseen terror assaults the Bebop crew.
（男）ビバップを襲った
いまだ かつてない恐怖
（フェイ）ひゃああああああああ
Caught by the venomous fangs of the unseen enemy, another victim falls.
（男）見えない敵の毒牙にかかり
また１人 犠牲者が
（ジェット）
のおおおおおおおおおおお！
What is the identity of the fearsome enemy that refuses to show itself?
（男）姿を見せぬ恐るべき敵とは
一体 何者か？
（エド）んにゃあああああああああ
A symphony of shivers that will send you into the deepest trenches of terror!
（男）
君を恐怖のどん底にたたき込む
戦慄のシンフォニー
Next episode: Toys in the Attic.
次回「闇夜のヘヴィ･ロック」
Once the channel is set, you will no longer be able to escape...
チャンネルを合わせたら
君は もう逃れられない